“伊利诺州州立惩戒中心”
“请勿搭载陌生人”
The Assistant Warden wants
this one out of the block early.
助理典狱长
要这家伙早点滚出去
Wants to get it over with fast.
越快搞定越好
Okay, let's do it.
动手吧！
Psst! Hey.
Come on, wake up,
it's time.
起来！时间到了
Wake up.
Let's go, it's time.
起床！时间到了
该走了
Well, this is it.
我们到了
7474505B.
犯人7474505B
What wing?
- Maximum wing, Block 9.
关在哪？
大角楼，第九区
Standard release?
服刑完毕？
Parole, three out of five.
Good behavior.
行为良好，提早假释
Give me a minute.
等一下
“杰克”
One Timex digital watch, broken.
坏掉的地摊电子表一只
One unused prophylactic.
没用过的保险套一个
One soiled.
用过的保险套一个
“艾伍德”
Boots, black.
Belt, black.
黑靴子、黑皮带
One black suit jacket.
黑外套一件
One pair black suit pants.
黑裤子一条
One hat. Black.
帽子一顶
黑的
One pair of sunglasses.
太阳眼镜一副
$23.07.
现金，23块7分钱
Sign here.
签收
片名：福禄双霸天
What's this?
这是什么？
什么意思？
What?
This car.
这部车
This stupid car.
这部破车
Where's the Cadillac?
凯迪拉克呢？
The Caddy. Where's the Caddy?
凯子车
那部凯子车呢？
The what?
什么车？
The Cadillac we used to have.
以前那部凯迪拉克
我们的布鲁斯专车
The Bluesmobile.
I traded it.
我把它卖了
You traded the Bluesmobile for this?
为了买这部烂车？
No, for a microphone.
不是，为了买麦克风
A microphone?
麦克风？
Okay, I can see that.
我了解了
What the hell is this?
那这又是什么？
This was a bargain.
这是物超所值
I picked it up at the Mount Prospect
City Police Auction last spring.
我去年在市警局的
拍卖会上买的
It's an old Mount Prospect police car.
They were practically giving them away.
这可是部退役警车
基本上是半买半送
Well, thank you, pal.
是哦！真是谢谢你
The day I get out of prison,
在我出狱的大喜之日…
my own brother picks me up in a police car.
我的亲兄弟
居然开部警车来接我
“芝加哥第95街桥”
“停”
You don't like it?
你不喜欢？
No, I don't like it.
我不喜欢
Car's got a lot of pickup.
加速性能不错
It's got a cop motor,
a 440 cubic-inch plant.
这部车有警用引擎
体积有440立方寸
It's got cop tires,
cop suspension, cop shocks.
还有警用轮胎
警用悬吊系统、避震器
It was a model made before catalytic converters
so it'll run good on regular gas.
这款车没有触媒转化器
所以非常省油
What do you say?
怎么样？
新的布鲁斯专车？
Is it the new Bluesmobile,
or what?
Fix the cigarette lighter.
买个新的点烟器
“圣海伦孤儿院”
“除暴安良”
What are we doing here?
我们来这干嘛？
You promised you'd visit the
Penguin the day you got out.
你说过一出狱
就要来拜访院长的
Yeah. So, I lied to her.
没错！我说谎
You can't lie to a nun.
不可以对修女说谎
We gotta go in and visit the Penguin.
我们一定要进去拜访她
No fucking way.
你做梦
Who is it?
哪位？
Jake and Elwood.
艾伍德，还有杰克
Come in.
进来
Hello, boys.
哈罗！小朋友
Nice to see you.
很高兴见到你们
Please, have a seat.
请坐
No, boys.
Come over here in front of me.
别这样，坐到前面来
I want to see your faces.
我要看到你们的脸
The county took a tax assessment
of this property last month.
库克郡政府
上个月征收土地税
They want $5,000.
我们要缴五千块的税
Doesn't the Church have to pay that?
教会打算付钱吗？
They would, if they were
interested in keeping the place.
如果他们不想孤儿院关门
就得缴税
But they aren't.
但是他们不打算付
The Archbishop wants to
sell this building outright
总主教想把孤儿院
卖给教育局
to the Board of Education.
What's gonna happen to you?
那你怎么办？
I'll be sent to the missions: Africa,
我会被派去传道
Latin America,
去非洲、中南美洲…
甚至韩国
Korea...
- Forget it.
$5,000? No problem.
五千块？小意思
明天早上就帮你搞定
We'll have it for you in the morning.
Let's go.
No. I will not take your filthy, stolen money!
不行
我不要你们偷来的脏钱
Well, then.
好吧！
你爱吃屎是你家的事
I guess you're really up shit creek.
I beg your pardon.
What did you say?
对不起
你刚才说什么？
I offered to help you.
我好心要帮你
You refused to take our money.
你不肯拿我的钱
Then I said, "I guess you're
really up shit creek. "
然后我说
“你爱吃屎是你家的事”
Ow! Christ, Jake,
take it easy, man.
杰克，别乱说话
艾伍德
Elwood!
妈的！
Jesus Christ!
老天爷！
Shit! Goddamn it!
干！
上帝！
干！机车
他妈的！
Son of a bitch!
Jesus Christ.
You son of a bitch!
老天爷！
他妈的！
You fat penguin!
死老太婆
Fuck this noise, man!
哇咧！
You are such a disappointing pair.
你们实在是太让我失望了
I prayed so hard for you.
我努力的为你们祷告
It saddens and hurts me
想起来我就伤心
that the two young men whom I raised
当年含辛茹苦
教养长大的孩子
to believe in the Ten Commandments,
have returned to me as two thieves
现在不但变成了小偷
with filthy mouths and bad attitudes.
而且满嘴脏话、态度恶劣
Get out!
And don't come back
滚出去！
除非你们改过自新
until you've redeemed yourselves.
否则永远都别回来
Boys, you gotta learn
not to talk to nuns that way.
孩子们！记住了
不能对修女讲脏话
Jake, Elwood.
杰克！艾伍德
Curtis!
- Hey, man!
寇帝斯！
You look fine, man!
气色不错嘛！
Good to see you, man!
见到你真好
Hey, buy you boys a drink?
要不要喝杯饮料？
Boys, things are bad.
孩子们！事情大条了
They gonna sell this place
to the Board of Education
他们要把孤儿院卖给教育局
and I'll be out on the street.
我就只好当无壳蜗牛了
That money's got to be in the Cook
County Assessor's Office within 11 days.
必须在11天之内
把钱交到税务局的办公室
They wouldn't turn you out, would they?
他们不会赶你出去吧？
Shit. What's one more old nigger
to the Board of Education?
不会才怪！
教育局要个老黑干嘛
Curtis, you and the Penguin
are the only family we got.
你和院长就是我们的家人
You're the only one
that was ever good to us
只有你是真的关心我们
singing Elmore James tunes and
blowing the harp for us down here.
在地下室唱歌
吹口琴给我们听
Well, the sister was right.
修女说的没错
你们应该上教堂
You boys could use a little churching up.
Slide on down to the Triple Rock
and catch Rev. Cleophus.
去三石浸信会找克里欧牧师
You boys listen to what he's got to say.
听他有什么话要说
Curtis,
寇帝斯
I don't want to listen
to no jive-ass preacher
我不想听什么狗屁牧师
说一堆废话
talking to me about heaven and hell.
Jake, you get wise.
You get to church.
杰克
聪明的话就给我上教堂
“三石浸信会教堂”
All I'm saying is we got to figure out
some way to get that money honestly.
我是说
我们得用正当的手段来筹钱
That could be a problem.
那问题就大了
It's like the Penguin says.
就像院长说的
We've got to make that
move towards redemption.
我们必须改过自新
我们应该上教堂
We got to go to church.
We've got to make that move towards redemption.
“我们应该改过自新
我们应该上教堂”
We got to go to church.
Bullshit.
放屁
Come on.
走吧！
And now,
this week's sermon
现在…
is from our beloved,
the Rev. Cleophus James!
本周由克里欧牧师
来为我们讲道
James.
Come on, Reverend!
- Come on, preacher.
And now, people.
各位兄弟姐妹们
Take your time!
And now, people.
各位兄弟姐妹们…
When I woke up this morning
今天早上我醒来以后
I heard a disturbing sound.
听到令人不安的声音
Yeah.
I said, when I woke up this morning
今天早上我醒来以后
I heard a disturbing sound!
听到令人不安的声音
What I heard was the jingle-jangle
我听到上千个失落的灵魂
发出的呻吟声
of a thousand lost souls!
I'm talking about the souls
of mortal men and women
我是指那些死去的男男女女
departed from this life!
失落的灵魂
Wait a minute!
等一下！
Those lost, anguished souls
roaming unseen over the earth,
这些失落、痛苦的灵魂
在人世间徘徊
seeking the divine light
寻找神的导引
they'll not find,
because it's too late!
却遍寻不获，只因太迟
Too late! Yeah!
Too late for them to ever see again
太迟了！
只因他们曾经背弃神
the light they once chose
not to follow. All right!
没错！
他们无法再得到神的导引
Don't be lost when your time comes!
救恩来临时，不要错过
"For the day of the Lord cometh
因为神将再次降临
"as a thief in the night. "
而且事先毫无预兆
Amen.
阿门！
Say Amen!
赞美主
Can I get Amen?
Let Us an All go back
让我们大家一同
一同回到
To the old Old landmark
回到旧时的
旧时的耶路撒冷
Let us an all go back
To the old Old landmark
Let us all all go back
As we stay in the service of the Lord
我们愿为神的仆人
Let us kneel
Kneel in prayer
让我们宣扬
宣扬神的福音
Gonna hold
Hold my breath
Let us kneel
Kneel in prayer
我们宣扬
宣扬福音到世界各角落
Gonna hold
Hold my breath
Let us feel
Feel that prayer
Kneel in prayer
实践、了解、感受
Let us preach
Preach the word
Got to preach Preach the word all the way
Do it, know it, feel it
Let us preach
Preach the word
Got to preach
all the way
Let's go
All the way
Yea, Lord
Gonna preach
Yeah, Lord
Yeah
Let's go
All the way
To the old
Old landmark
Let's go
All the way
To the old
Old landmark
Let's go
All the way
To the old
Old landmark
Yeah
I know
Jake, are you all right?
你没事吧？杰克
Oh, Child
Say it loud
Hallelujah
哈利路亚
The band.
乐队
乐团
Do you see the light?
你看到荣光了吗？
The band!
乐团
Do you see the light?
你看到荣光了吗？
What light?
什么光啊？
Have you seen the light?
你有没有看到荣光？
Yes! Jesus H.
Tap-Dancing Christ!
看到了！
看到耶稣哇咧基督
I have seen the light!
我看到荣光啦！
The band, Elwood,
the band!
乐团啊！艾伍德
乐团
The band?
乐团？
The band.
乐团
Band.
乐团？乐团
The band!
Praise God!
赞美主！
And God bless the United States of America.
愿主保佑美国
All go back
To the old
Old landmark
Let us all
All go back
To the old
Old landmark
Let us all
All go back
To the old
Old landmark
Do it, know ft, feel it
Gonna go back
All go back
Stay in the service
of the Lord
愿为神的仆人
Yea, Lord
感谢主！
“精选专辑”
We'll put the band back together,
do a few gigs.
我们重新组团
参加几场表演
We get some bread.
Bang. $5,000.
我们马上就可以赚到五千块
Yeah, getting the band back together
might not be that easy, Jake.
要重新组团或许没那么容易
What are you talking about?
你是什么意思？
They split.
They all took straight jobs.
解散以后
大家都找到了工作
Yeah? So you know where they are.
反正你知道他们在哪
You said you were keeping
in touch with them.
你不是有和他们保持联络
I got a couple of leads,
a few phone numbers.
我是有些线索
有几个电话号码
But I mean, how many of them
visited or even wrote you, huh?
但是他们有谁去看过你
或者写过信给你？
They're not the kind of
guys who write letters.
他们本来就是“信”无能
You were outside.
I was inside.
你在外面，我在里面
You were supposed to keep
in touch with the band.
你本来就该和他们保持联络
I kept asking you if we
were gonna play again.
我一直问你有没有机会复出
What was I gonna do,
take away your only hope?
不然该怎么办？
让你失去唯一的希望
Take away the very thing
that kept you going in there?
让你失去继续下去的力量？
I took the liberty of bullshitting you.
Okay?
我只是没有实话实说
You lied to me.
你骗我
It wasn't lies.
It was just bullshit.
那不叫骗，那叫瞒
What?
干！
怎么了？
Rollers.
No.
条子
不是吧！
Yeah.
就是
干！
What? What did I do?
怎样？干嘛拦我？
You failed to stop at a red signal.
你闯红灯违规
The light was yellow, sir.
我闯的是黄灯
May I see your license, please?
麻烦把驾照、行照拿出来
God damn it!
见鬼了！
Man, I haven't been pulled
over in six months.
我六个月没被警察拦过
I bet those cops have got SCMODS.
我打赌每辆警车上
都有装SCMODS
SCMODS?
什么是SCMODS？
State County Municipal Offender Data System.
州、郡、市立
违法者资料系统
“艾伍德布鲁斯：驾照吊销”
“欠缴罚单：共计172张”
“逮捕驾驶，扣押车辆”
Elwood, we show your license
currently under suspension.
艾伍德，你的驾照已经被吊销了
Step out of the car, please.
请你下车
First you trade the Cadillac for a microphone.
Then you lie to me about the band.
你先是卖掉凯迪拉克
去买麦克风
然后是骗我乐团的事
Now you're gonna put me
right back in the joint.
现在是要害我被关回去
They're not gonna catch us.
We're on a mission from God.
他们捉不到我们的
我们是上帝派来的
Elwood.
艾伍德
We are in high-speed pursuit
northbound on Courtland Avenue.
嫌犯由庭院街往北高速逃逸
Black-and-white 1974 Dodge
sedan with Illinois plates.
驾驶伊利诺州车牌
1974年的道奇轿车
Request assistance.
请求支援
We'll be all right if we can
just get back on the expressway.
等到我们开上快速道路
就没事了
This don't look like no expressway to me!
我怎么看都不像是快速道路
Don't yell at me.
别凶嘛！
What do you want me to do, motorhead?
不然要怎样？猪头
Try not to be so negative all the time.
别老是这么悲观
Why don't you offer some constructive criticism?
你可以提出建设性的批评
You got us into this parking lot, pal.
是你要开进停车场的
快点把我们弄出去
Now you get us out!
You want out of this parking lot? Okay.
想离开停车场？没问题
Will there be anything else?
还需要什么吗？
Yes. Do you have a Miss Piggy?
你们有没有猪小姐？
There's Hanson Burgers.
你看！汉堡店
Yeah, lots of space in this mall.
这家百货公司蛮大的
Disco pants and haircuts.
迪斯可服装、发型屋
Yeah.
Baby clothes.
婴儿服
This place has got everything.
真的是应有尽有
New Oldsmobiles are in early this year.
下一年度的通用新车
已经上市了
Pier 1 imports.
家具店
妈呀！
They broke my watch!
他们把我的手表弄坏了
I'm gonna catch that sucker
不管付出什么代价
if it's the last thing I ever do.
我非抓到那个混蛋不可
“高压电危险”
“旅馆只收男客，欢迎暂住”
Nice place, huh?
地方不错吧？
Hey, Sam.
嗨！山姆
Hey, Lloyd.
嗨！洛伊
Anybody call for me on the phone?
有没有人打电话找我？
No. No calls.
没有
Some guy left this card.
Cop. Said he'd be back.
有人留了名片给你
是警察，说他还会再来
“伊利诺州惩戒局”
This here's my brother, Jake.
He just got out of the joint.
这是我哥哥，杰克
他刚出狱
He's gonna be staying
with me for a few weeks.
暂时过来住几个礼拜
Yeah. Okay.
没问题
Did you get me my Cheez Whiz, boy?
帮我买起士酱了吗？孩子
Well, it ain't much,
but it's home.
虽然简陋
但毕竟是自己的家
How often does the train go by?
- So often you won't even notice it.
火车多久经过一次？
多到你会习惯
What are you doing?
- Making dinner. Want some?
你在干嘛？
准备晚餐
你要不要？
No.
不要
Tomorrow we got to get
the band back together.
明天开始把团员找回来
I'm gonna quit work in the
morning, first thing.
我明天一大早
就先去把工作辞掉
And how are you going to get to work,
Mr. Lead Foot,
你要怎么去辞职？
猪头飙车王
Mr. Hot Redder,
Mr. Motor Head?
Those cops took your license away.
警察没收了你的驾照
They got your name,
your address.
他们知道你的姓名、地址
No, they don't got my address.
错！他们不知道
我用的是假地址
I falsified my renewal.
I put down 1060 West Addison.
驾照上写的是
1060西艾迪生街
1060 West Addison?
1060西艾迪生街？
That's Wrigley Field.
菲尔德球场
I gotta hit the sack.
我得休息一下
Hey, you sleaze! My bed!
有没有搞错？那是我的床
This, gentlemen, is the elegant
abode of one Elwood Blues.
各位，这就是艾伍德的狗窝
Thanks for your help,
Mr. Mercer.
谢谢帮忙！梅塞先生
I kind of like the Wrigley Field bit.
我比较喜欢菲尔德球场
Yeah, real cute.
是哦！你真幽默
All right, Sam?
嗨！山姆
Hi, has my friend arrived yet?
我朋友回来了吗？
他昨天就没向我报到
Failed to report in yesterday.
I don't want no trouble.
我不想惹麻烦
You just tell us where they are
and there'll be no trouble.
跟我们合作就不会有麻烦
Stand back.
退后
It's almost 9:00.
We've gotta go to work.
快要九点了
我们该去上班了
Well, Elwood,
sit down.
艾伍德，请坐
有什么事吗？
What's on your mind?
I got to quit.
我要辞职
Why is that, Elwood?
为什么？
I'm going to become a priest.
我要去当牧师
Well, okay.
好吧！
Listen, I'll call payroll and have
them get your severance pay ready.
我会叫会计室帮你结算薪水
Good luck.
祝你好运
God bless you, sir.
- Well, thank you.
愿主保佑你
谢谢你
What's this?
这是什么？
This is the last known address
是“骨头”汤姆
还有“忧郁”路易
of "Bones" Malone and "Blue Lou" Marini.
最后一次搬家的地址
The Lord works in mysterious ways.
天主的作功神妙难解
Yeah.
没错
Mrs. Toronto?
你是多伦多太太？
Tarantino.
是泰伦铁诺
Ma'am, do you have a Thomas Malone
or Louis Marini living here?
汤姆马龙和路易马瑞尼
是不是住这儿？
Not anymore.
They moved out a long time ago.
没有，他们早就搬走了
I don't take in boarders,
not for a long time.
我已经不招房客了
May we come in, ma'am?
- Please.
我们可以进去吗？
请进
Did they leave a forwarding address?
A phone number?
他们有没有留下转信地址？
电话号码？
No.
没有
Did they live quietly?
What were their personal habits?
他们生活习惯如何？
吵不吵？
They were good boys
他们是好房客
but they made a lot of racket at night.
不过晚上很吵
Are you the police?
你们是警察？
No, ma'am.
We're musicians.
不，我们是音乐家
Mr. Man!
先生！
先生
Yes, ma'am?
什么事？
They left this card.
Maybe it'll help you?
他们留下一张名片
或许帮的上忙
“墨飞与魔音
包办各种喜庆宴会”
Thanks.
谢谢
“假日酒店”
“墨飞与魔音”
Thank you.
You're marvelous.
谢谢各位的掌声
Thank you.
谢谢！我是墨飞
这些是魔音乐团的成员…
I'm Murph, and these
are the Magic Tones.
Steve "The Colonel" Cropper,
Donald "Duck" Dunn,
“上校”史蒂夫古柏
“唐老鸭”唐诺德唐
Willie "Too Big" Hall
and Tom "Bones" Malone.
“大条”威利霍尔
“骨头”汤姆马龙
We'll be back for the Armada Room's two-hour
disco swing party after this short break.
休息片刻将继续带给您
两小时的魔音迪斯可舞会
Till then,
don't you go changing.
别走开，我们马上回来
So, Jake, you're out. You're free.
You're rehabilitated.
你被放出来
重获自由、改过自新
What's next? What's happening?
What you gonna do?
下一步打算干嘛？
有什么计划？
You got the money you owe us, motherfucker?
你现在有钱还我们吗？混蛋
Look, let's just get something straight here...
让我们把事情搞清楚
The reason he got locked in
the slam in the first place
就是为了要帮你们付钱
was for sticking up a gas
station to cover you guys.
害他跑去抢加油站
还被关了起来
You're kidding.
你开玩笑吧！
He pulled that job to pay for
the band's room-service tab
他去抢劫是因为
乐团付不出旅馆钱
from that Kiwanis gig in Coal City.
就是煤城的那场表演
You did?
That's right.
真的吗？
没错
So I don't want to hear anymore
of this small-change shit.
所以我不想再听到有谁
说我欠他钱
We're putting the band back together.
我们要重新组团
Now, who here at this table
你们之间…
can honestly say
that they played any finer
有谁敢大声说
他表演的或者混的
or felt any better than they did than
when they were with the Blues Brothers?
比以前还要好
You were the backbone.
你们这群台柱
The nerve center of a great
rhythm-and-blues band.
是我们节奏蓝调乐团
成功的原因
You can make that live,
breathe and jump again.
你们可以重振往日的雄风
"Murph and the Magic Tones?"
墨飞与魔音？
Look at you in those
candy-ass monkey suits.
看看你们身上穿的西装
And I thought I had it bad in Joliet.
比我的牢服还要逊
At least we got a change
in clothes, sucker.
至少我们有改变造型
You're wearing the same shit
you had on three years ago.
那像你的造型三年如一日
Jake ain't lying.
杰克说的没错
We had a band powerful enough to
turn goat piss into gasoline.
我们以前的乐团真不是盖的
We'll never get that fat sound again.
- Not without some more horns.
可是没有喇叭手是搞不定的
We'll never get Mr. Fabulous.
我们请不到ㄅㄚˇㄅㄨ的
Where is he?
Forget it.
他人呢？
别想了！
Mr. Fabulous is the top
maitre d' at the Chez Paul.
ㄅㄚˇㄅㄨ
现在可是法国餐厅的经理
He's pulling down six bills a week.
一星期可以赚到六百块
Matt Murphy got married.
连麦特墨非都结婚了
Where is Matt "Guitar" Murphy?
“吉他”麦特墨非去哪了？
He opened a soul food restaurant
with his old lady on Maxwell Street.
他和他女朋友合开了间餐厅
And he took Blue Lou with him.
他找“忧郁”路易去帮忙
You'll never get Matt and Mr. Fabulous
out of them high-paying gigs.
不可能叫麦特和ㄅㄚˇㄅㄨ
放弃他们的高薪职业的
Oh, yeah?
是吗？
Well, me and the Lord,
we got an understanding.
我和神之间…
我们达成共识
We're on a mission from God.
我们是上帝派来的
Mainly French cuisine.
我们以法国料理为主
No, sir. Mayor Daley no longer dines here.
不，达利市长不来敝店用餐
先生，他早就死了
He's dead, sir.
Private dining rooms are available.
有私人宴会厅
Oh, no. I thought it was
supposed to be 5 years.
天哪！不是应该是五年吗？
Didn't you get 5 years?
Uh, no, sir, not you.
你不是得关五年吗？
不，不是说你
And your name, sir?
请问贵姓大名？
Rizzolo, for 8 at 11:30.
Thank you.
瑞索洛，11点半八个人
没问题
Mr. Fabulous, how marvelous
it is to see you.
ㄅㄚˇㄅㄨ
真高兴看到你
You're looking younger than ever.
你的气色不错嘛！
Wait.
You guys can't come in here.
等一下！我不欢迎你们
Oh, nonsense, my dear fellow.
老兄！别闹了
My brother and I have come to dine
我们两兄弟是来吃饭…
to celebrate my early release
from the service of the state.
庆祝我提早假释出狱的
Wait. Let's talk outside.
不如我们去外面谈
去喝杯咖啡
Let's have a cup of coffee outside.
Why, heavens, no.
为什么要出去？
We seek a full meal and all
the compliments of the house.
我们是专程来让你请客的
Come, Elwood.
走吧！艾伍德
Let us adjourn ourselves to the nearest table
让我们去最近的餐桌坐下来
and overlook this establishment's board of fare.
就偶尔奢侈一次好了
Good evening.
Chez Paul. Wait! Hey!
您好！保罗的餐厅
站住
Uh, sir, do you mind calling back
in about five minutes, please?
能不能麻烦您
过几分钟再打来？
I'm sure, we'll have a table
for you in just a few moments.
马上就轮到两位了
Excuse me, won't you?
失陪一下
Give us a bottle of your finest champagne,
我们要一瓶最好的香槟
five shrimp cocktails
and some bread for my brother.
鸡尾酒虾
还有拿点面包给我弟弟
We have a Dom Perignon, '71, at $120.
最好的香槟是1971年的
一瓶要120元
That'll be fine, pal.
可以
Come on. Seriously, you guys, the
food here is really expensive.
别闹了！这家餐厅很贵的
一碗汤就要妈的十块钱
The soup is fucking $10.
Come on. Let's go outside.
I'll buy you a cup of coffee.
干脆我请你们出去喝咖啡
We're putting the band back together.
我们要重新组团
Forget it. No way.
少来了！做梦
We're on a mission from God.
我们是上帝派来的
Hold it, hold it.
What's this?
等一下！这是干嘛？
Waiter? Sir?
服务生？
Please, waiter?
服务生？麻烦你过来一下
Yes, sir?
How are your salads?
是不是沙拉不合胃口？
The salads are fine.
沙拉很好吃！只是我们…
It's just that we'd like
to move to another table,
我们想换到
离他们远一点的位子
away from those two gentlemen.
Why? Have they been disturbing you?
- No.
是不是他们骚扰您？
不是，实在是…
It's just that, well, frankly,
they're offensive... smelling.
是因为他们讨人厌的味道
I mean, they smell bad.
我是说他们身上有臭味
Excuse me, sir. I'll see if I can
locate another table for you.
很抱歉！我尽量帮您想办法
Thank you.
谢谢
Wrong glass, sir.
您用错杯子了
How much for the little girl?
小女孩要多少钱？
The women?
How much for the women?
女人？女人要多少钱？
What?
什么？
Your women,
I want to buy your women.
我要买你家的女人
你的女儿
The little girl.
Your daughters.
把你的女儿卖给我
把小孩卖给我
Sell them to me.
Sell me your children.
Maitre d'! Maitre d'!
经理！
Hey, cut it out,
cut it out.
别闹了！
不然老板会叫我报警
The owners are gonna ask me
to call the cops.
You wouldn't do that to me,
would you, man?
你不会真的报警吧？
He just got out of Joliet.
他才刚从监狱假释出来
He's on parole.
You can't call the cops on him, man.
We're putting the band back together.
你不能叫警察来捉他
我们要重组乐团
I said no.
Absolutely not!
我说过，不行就是不行
You! How much for your wife?
你太太要多少钱？
We're putting the band back together.
我们要重组乐团
我们需要你的喇叭
We need you, man.
We need your horn.
I can't. I really can't.
我真的不行
We got everybody except Matt "Guitar" Murphy
and Blue Lou and we're getting them next.
我们已经找到了其他人
只剩下麦特和路易
我们接着会去找他们
No way.
不行
If you say no, Elwood and I
will come here for breakfast,
如果你拒绝…
我跟艾伍德会每天三餐
都来光顾你的生意
lunch and dinner every day of the week.
Okay, okay. I'll play.
You got me.
算你狠！我参加
行了吧？
经理？
White men!
白种男人
White women!
白种女人
The swastika is calling you!
万字旗正在呼唤你
The sacred and ancient symbol of your race
自宇宙开创之初
便代表你们种族…
since the beginning of time.
神圣、古老的象征
The Jew is using the black
犹太人利用黑人…
as muscle against you.
为武器来攻击你们
And you are left there,
helpless.
而你们只能坐以待毙
Fuck you! Why don't you
go back where you belong?
去你的！
What are you gonna do about it, Whitey?
你们该怎么办？白人们
Just sit there?
袖手旁观吗？
Go back where you came from!
滚回老家去！
Of course not!
当然不是
Son of a bitch!
成为我们的一员
You are going to join with us,
the members of the American Socialist
White People's Party. '
加入我们
加入美国社会主义白人党
an organization of decent,
正派的社团组织
law-abiding white folk
守法的白人成员
just like you.
就像你们一样
Blow it out your ass,
you bastards!
去死吧！混蛋
Go to hell!
去死吧！
I pledge allegiance to Adolf Hitler.
我宣誓效忠希特勒
The immortal leader of our race.
我们不朽的领袖
To the order for which he stands.
为了他所坚持的秩序
And to the order for which he stands.
One great cause.
一项了不起的运动
Sacred and invincible.
神圣不可侵犯
Hey, what's going on?
怎么回事？
Those bums won their court case,
so they're marching today.
那些烂人在游行
庆祝官司打赢了
What bums?
哪些烂人？
The fucking Nazi Party.
那些该死的纳粹党
Illinois Nazis.
伊利诺纳粹
I hate Illinois Nazis.
我讨厌伊利诺纳粹
Heil Hitler!
- Heil Hitler!
希特勒万岁！
Ten hut!
立正！
Gruppenführer!
古泡芙
是的！长官
Yes, sir!
Gruppenführer, get that
car's license plate number.
记下那辆车的车牌号码
We're gonna kill that son of a bitch.
我们要杀了那个王八蛋
“南方心灵美食店”
Boom, boom, DOOITI, DOOITI
Come on home, babe
回来吧！宝贝
Oh, come on home
回来吧！辣妹
Oh, come on home,
come on home to me, babe
回来吧！漂亮宝贝
I love you
我爱你
Come on
come on, come on
Oh, come on home
Come on, I love ya
Hold me
I know
I love you
Look out
When she walk that walk
当她风情万种
And talk that talk
当她热情如火
And whisper in my ear
在我耳边耳语
Tell me that she love me
告诉我你爱我
I love that talk
我爱听你说
That baby talk
稚气的话语
When she talk like that
你的热情挑逗
I can't take it like that
让我无法抗拒
Haw, haw, haw, haw
Hey, hey, yeah
Come on home,
pretty babe
宝贝，回到我的身边
Walk your walk
风情万种，热情如火
Talk your talk
Talk your talk, baby
宝贝，你热情如火
Talk
Yeah.
不错！
Thank you,
ladies and gentlemen.
谢谢各位先生女士
That was Boom Boom, the song
that I wrote, back in the '50s
刚才演唱的
是我50年代写的一首歌
No, you didn't.
才不是你写的
那可是畅销曲
...was such a big hit.
不是你写的
是我写的
No, you didn't!
I wrote Boom Boom.
那首歌是我写的，是我写的歌
Can I help you, boys?
要吃点什么？
You got any white bread?
有没有白吐司？
Yes.
有
I'll have some toasted
white bread, please.
我要烤过的白吐司
You want butter or jam
on that toast, honey?
上面要不要涂牛油
或者果酱？
No, ma'am. Dry.
什么都不要涂
Got any fried chicken?
有没有炸鸡？
Best damn chicken in the state.
- Bring me four fried chickens and a Coke.
我们的炸鸡好吃到吓吓叫
我要四只炸鸡和一瓶可乐
You want chicken wings or chicken legs?
- Four fried chickens and a Coke.
你要鸡翅膀还是鸡腿？
我要四只炸鸡和一瓶可乐
And some dry white toast, please.
还有纯的白吐司
You all want anything to drink with that?
- No, ma'am. - A Coke.
要不要喝点饮料？
不要
一瓶可乐
Be up in a minute.
马上就好
We got two honkies out there
外面来了两个白人
穿的像是卖钻石的
dressed like Hasidic diamond merchants.
Say what?
你说什么？
They look like they're from
the CIA or something.
他们打扮的像中情局探员
What they wanna eat?
他们点什么？
The tall one wants white bread. Toast.
高的那个要吃烤白吐司
Dry. With nothing on it.
上面什么都不要涂
Elwood!
是艾伍德
And the other one wants four
whole fried chickens and a Coke.
另外一个要四只炸全鸡
和一瓶可乐
And Jake! Shit!
The Blues Brothers!
是杰克！老天
是布鲁斯兄弟
Hi, Jake.
嗨！杰克
Matt! How you doing?
你好吗？麦特
How you doing?
How was Joliet?
大锅饭好吃吗？
Oh, it's bad.
难吃透了！
星期四晚上都吃青椒牛排
On Thursday night they serve
a wicked pepper steak.
Can't be as bad as the cabbage rolls
at the Terre Haute Federal Pen.
不会比联邦监狱的
包心菜卷难吃
Or that oatmeal at the Cook County Slammer.
They're all pretty bad.
或者是郡立监狱的燕麦片
全部一样难吃
Matt! Me and Elwood,
麦特，我和艾伍德
我们要重新组团
we're putting the band back together.
We need you and Blue Lou.
我们需要你还有路易
Oh, man. Don't talk that way around here.
千万别提起这件事
我老婆…她会杀了我
My old lady,
she'll kill me.
Ma'am, you gotta understand.
太太，你要了解
This is a lot bigger
than any domestic problems
这件事比你想像的还要大条
you might be experiencing.
Matt, what the hell is he talking about?
- Don't get riled, sugar.
他在胡说什么啊？
别生气！宝贝
Don't you,
"don't get riled, sugar" me!
少来这套
Now, you not going back on the road no more.
我不准你去巡回表演
And you ain't playing any more
two-bit, sleazy dives.
不准去那些低级酒吧演奏
You're living with me now.
And you're not gonna go sliding around
你现在跟我住
别想跟你的无赖朋友
出去鬼混
with your old white hoodlum friends.
But, babes!
This is Jake and Elwood!
可是，他们是杰克和艾伍德
是布鲁斯兄弟
The Blues Brothers!
布鲁斯兄弟
狗屁
They still owe you money, fool!
白痴！他们还欠你钱耶
Ma'am, would it make you feel
any better if you knew that
太太
如果你知道我们来找他
what we're asking Matt
here to do is a holy thing?
是为了完成一件神圣的使命
就不会反对了
You see,
we're on a mission from God.
其实是上帝派我们来的
Don't you blaspheme in here!
你少在这里放屁
Now, this is my man,
this is my restaurant,
这是我的餐厅
他可是我的老公
and you two are gonna just
walk right out that door,
你们两个立刻给我滚出去
without your dry, white toast,
without your four fried chickens
别想吃烤白吐司
别想吃炸全鸡
and without Matt "Guitar" Murphy!
更别想带走麦特
Now, you listen to me!
I love you.
现在换你听我说，我爱你
But I'm the man and you're the woman.
但我是个大男人
And I'll make the decisions
concerning my life!
我能够自己做决定
You better think about what you saying.
你最好想清楚再说
You better think about the
consequences of your actions.
你最好想清楚后果再做
Oh, shut up, woman!
闭嘴！女人
You better think
- Think
你最好想
Think about what you're trying to do to me
想清楚要怎么对我
Yeah, think
Think, think
Let your mind go
Let yourself be free
敞开胸怀，解放自我
Let's go back
让我们回到
Let's go way on back when
让我们回到从前
I didn't even know you
我还不认识你
你只是个小鬼
You couldn't have been too much more than 10
Just a child
I ain't no psychiatrist
I ain't no doctor with degrees
我不是心理医生
不知道你想什么
It don't take too much high IQ
to see what you're doing to me
笨蛋都能看出来
你是怎么对我的
You better think
Think
你最好想
Think about what you're trying to do to me
想清楚要怎么对我
Think
Think, think
想清楚
Let your mind go
Let yourself be free
敞开胸怀，解放自我
Oh, freedom
Freedom
自由
Yeah, freedom
Right now, freedom
Freedom
Oh, freedom right now
Hey, think about it
想清楚
You, think about it
你给我想清楚
There ain't nothing you could ask
I could answer you, but I won't
以前对你，我是有求必应
But I was gonna change that, I'm not
if you keep doing things I don't
现在对你，我决定看心情
Think about what you're trying to do to me
想清楚要怎么对我
Damn it
Think
该死
Let your mind go
Let yourself be free
敞开胸怀，解放自我
People walking around every day
playing games and taking scores
每天人来人往，勾心斗角
Tryin' to make other people lose their mind
占人便宜，你自己要小心
Be careful you don't lose yours
Hey, think
Think
Think about what you're trying to do to me
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Think, think
Let your mind go
Let yourself be free
You need me
Need me
你需要我
And I need you
Don't you know
我需要你
Without each other there
ain't nothing either can do
我们俩人是天生的一对
Yeah, think about it, babe
宝贝，想清楚
What you trying to do to me
想清楚要怎么对我
To the bone, man
Think about it right now
仔细的想，立刻想清楚
Oh, freedom
Freedom
自由
Yeah, freedom
Freedom
Right now
You, think about it
你给我想清楚
There ain't nothing you could ask
I can answer you, but I won't
以前对你，我是有求必应
But I was gonna change my mind
if you keep doing things I don't
现在对你，我决定看心情
Yeah, think
Think
Think about what you're trying to do to me
Let your mind go
Let yourself be free
You need me
Need me
你需要我
And I need you
Don't you know
我需要你
Without each other there
ain't nothing either can do
我们俩人是天生的一对
Yeah, yeah
Think about it, baby
宝贝，想清楚
想清楚要怎么对我
What you're trying
to do to me
To the bone, man
仔细的想
Think about it, baby
宝贝，想清楚
Yeah, right on
To the bone
立刻
仔细的想
For deepness
To the bone, for deepness
仔细的想
好好的想
Yeah
To the bone
For deepness, think about it
To the bone, for deepness
好好的想
Right now
现在
Think about it,
yeah, yeah, yeah
想清楚
To the bone, for deepness
仔细的想
好好的想
Think about it
For deepness
想清楚
仔细的想
Don't give me the blues,
brother, hey
管他什么布鲁斯兄弟
You had better
你最好
Stop and think about it
Think
别做梦
想清楚
Let's boogie.
上路吧！
Well, go ahead, damn it!
看什么看？还不走
干！
“烫、染发美容院”
“M79火焰喷射器”
Pardon me, but we do have a strict policy
concerning the handling of the instruments.
对不起！
本店对于顾客试用乐器
有严格的规定
An employee of Ray's Music
Exchange must be present.
就是“雷乐器交换店”的员工
必须在场
Now, may I help you?
有什么需要帮忙的？
Ray, it's me. Joliet Jake.
是我啊！雷
“惩戒所”杰克
I once rented some column
speakers from you for my band,
我曾经为我的乐团
“布鲁斯兄弟”
跟你租过音箱
The Blues Brothers.
Hey, Ray. it's me, Murph, of
Murph and the Magic Tones.
嗨！雷
我是“墨飞与魔音”的墨飞
Remember me?
I bought three Fender amps.
记得吗？我买过三个扩音器
Oh, we sell a lot of amplifiers.
我卖过的扩音器可多了
Not like these.
They were beautiful.
我买的可是名牌货
Upholstered with thick,
red shag.
外面还包了一层红绒布
Oh, right, right!
I remember now.
对哦！
As a matter of fact, I'll buy
them all back for $350 a piece.
想起来了
我用一个三百五买了回来
$350?
三百五？
I paid $800 each,
not 6 months ago.
我买了不到六个月
一个就花了我八百块
Well, you know depreciation, man.
东西总会折旧嘛！老兄
Ray, we're here to buy stuff.
我们是来买东西的
We need pianos,
amps, mikes, the works.
我们表演需要钢琴
扩音器、麦克风
Now, go on! Get!
滚出去！
Breaks my heart,
a boy that young going bad.
看到小孩子变坏最让人伤心
Tell me a little about this
electric piano, Ray.
告诉我这台电子琴如何
Oh, you have a good eye, my man.
老兄，你很有眼光
That's the best in the city of Chicago.
那可是全芝加哥
最好的电子琴
How much?
多少钱？
$2,000 and it's yours.
You can take it home with you.
只要花两千块就是你的
买回家去，保证你物超所值
Matter of fact, I'll throw
in the black keys for free.
$2,000 for this chunk of shit?
两千块买这么台烂琴？
Come on, Ray!
你不是开玩笑吧！
I mean, really, Ray.
It's used.
拜托！雷
连弹出来的声音都不准
There's no action left in this keyboard.
Excuse me.
借过
I don't think there's anything wrong
with the action on this piano.
谁说键盘弹出来的声音不准
Well, singing about the
fella you've been dancing with
我听朋友说你跟邻居们
All over the neighborhood
街头巷尾跳不停
So, why didn't you ask me, baby
宝贝，何不邀请我
Or didn't you think I could?
难道你认为我不行
Well, I know that the
boogaloo is out of sight
我知道你嫌我落伍
But the shingaling's the thing tonight
搞不清楚流行什么
But if that was you and me out there, baby
如果你肯跟我跳舞
I would have shown you how to do it right
我绝对会秀给你看
Do it right
给你看
Twisting
转啊转
Shake it, shake it, baby
让我们摇啊摇
Here we go loop de loop
我们拍拍手
Shake it out, baby
宝贝，用力摇
Here we go loop de la
我们跳跳脚
Bend over
弯下腰，摇摇你的屁股
Let me see you shake your tailfeather
Bend over
Come on
来吧！宝贝
摇摇你的屁股
Let me see you shake your tailfeather
Come on Let me see you
shake your tailfeather
Come on
Come on, baby
来吧！宝贝
Come on
Yeah, come on, baby
All right
好
Do the twist
我们转
Do the fly
我们飞
Do the swim
我们游
And do the bird
我们摇头
Do the duck
我们摆臀
Do the monkey
我们挥手
Watusi
扭腰
And what about the frug
我们转圈
Do the mashed potato
我们点脚
What about the boogaloo
大家开心跳
The Bony Maronie
街头巷尾跳不停
Come on, let's do the twist
让我们转啊转
Ah, twisting
转啊转
Shake it, shake it, baby
让我们摇啊摇
Twisting
Shake it, shake it, baby
Okay, man.
好吧！老兄
We'll take
these axes.
这些乐器我们买了
Naturally. And as usual,
I gotta take an IOU.
当然啦！
老规矩，你们得写借据
You guys go inside,
get yourselves a bite.
你们先进去叫东西吃
I've got to
make a phone call.
我要去打通电话
Now, Jake, does this phone
call concern our first gig?
是不是和我们
第一场表演有关？
Have I ever lied to you?
我有骗过你吗？
What are we gonna do, man?
我们该怎么办？
根本没有表演
We don't got no gig.
How much money you got?
身上有钱吗？
I got a quarter.
有个两毛五的铜板
That's enough for a phone call. Come on.
够打电话
走吧！
“丙烷：绝对禁止吸烟”
What are you doing, Elwood?
你进来干嘛？
You said we were gonna make a call.
是你说我们要打电话的
I said I was gonna make a call.
我说我要打电话
Who are you gonna call, Jake?
你要打给谁？
Do you remember Maury Sline?
记得莫瑞史莱吗？
Sline? Booking agent?
What about him?
史莱？表演经纪人？
他怎么样
He got us some good showcases in the old days.
他以前帮我们签过不少合约
He got us the Morgan Park,
he got us the Tick Took.
像是摩根公园、滴答酒吧
I got him laid.
He owes me.
他都是靠我认识辣妹的
Give it a shot.
试试看吧！
Hey, Jake.
喂！杰克
There's got to be at least
$7 worth of change here.
这里至少有七块钱的零钱
Yeah?
Sir.
长官
What did you find out?
有什么发现？
Okay.
听好了
I called a friend at
the Motor Vehicle Department.
我联络了在监理所工作的朋友
That license plate is like a
rash all over the computer.
电脑一下就查到那个车牌号码
The car belongs to a known traffic menace.
车子是一个危险驾驶的
What's his name?
叫什么名字？
His name is Elwood Blues.
车主叫艾伍德布鲁斯
He's got a record a mile long.
他的违规记录是落落长
而且他是天主教徒
And he's a Catholic.
Did you get his address?
- Of course.
有没有地址？
当然有
1060 West Addison.
1060西艾迪生街
Let's go.
我们走
“菲尔德球场
芝加哥小熊队的家”
“西艾迪生街”
Anybody with that kind of record
is gonna make a mistake.
有那种驾驶记录的人
想不违规很难
I want all party members in the tri-state
district to monitor the city, county,
通知三州交界区的所有党员
监听市、郡和州警的
无线电通话
and state police on their C.B's.
Mr. Blues is gonna fuck up.
布鲁斯先生一定会搞砸的
And when he does,
只要一出状况
he better pray the police
get to him before we do.
他最好祈祷警察比我们
先逮到他
好！独奏
All right, man.
我们已经开了三个小时
到底是要去哪？
We've been in this car
for three hours now.
Where the hell is this place?
I told you it'd take
a little while to get there.
我说过要开一段路才能到
What's the name of the place?
那是什么地方？
Uh, the name of the place is, uh,
那个地方叫…
Bob's Country Bunker.
巴布的乡间仓库
Here we are.
我们到了
Bob's Country Bunker?
巴布的乡间仓库
“老好男孩乐团今晚演出”
Jake,
the sign says,
招牌上说
老好男孩乐团今晚演出
"Tonight only, the Good Ole Boys. "
Blues Brothers!
应该是“布鲁斯兄弟乐团”
It should read,
"Tonight only,
"the Blues Brothers' triumphant return. "
“布鲁斯兄弟今晚光荣复出”
Must be some kind of mistake.
一定是弄错了
You guys unload the stuff.
你们先把东西卸下来
Elwood, come with me.
艾伍德，你跟我来
What can I get you boys?
两位需要什么？
You thirsty, you hungry
or just driving through?
要喝点、吃点什么？
还是只是路过
Maybe you'd like a beer,
or something a little harder?
要来杯啤酒还是来杯烈酒？
We happen to make the
state's best pepper steak.
我们有全州最好吃的
青椒牛排
No, thank you, ma'am!
谢谢！不用了
We may be sucking back a few
beers a little later on.
我们可能晚一点再喝
We'll be here all night.
You see, we're the band.
反正我们整晚都会在
因为要表演
You are?
Oh, gee, that's nice!
原来是你们？太好了！
Hey, Bob,
this is the band!
巴布，乐团到了
All right!
太好了！
What kind of music
do you usually have here?
你们通常都演奏哪种音乐？
We got both kinds.
We got country and western.
乡村音乐和西部音乐
两种都有
Jake, are you sure
this is the place?
你确定是这里没错？
Yeah! Sure!
This is the place.
当然确定！是这里没错
Hi! You the Good Ole Boys?
That's us!
你们就是老好男孩？
就是我们！
The rest of the band's
out in the parking lot
其他团员正在停车场搬乐器
getting our stuff together.
Well, I'm sure glad
to have you boys here.
真高兴能请到你们来表演
I'm Bob and this here is my place.
我是巴布，这儿的老板
It's a beautiful place, Bob!
你的餐厅很漂亮
I guess you wanna get your
steel guitars and everything
你们一定需要
把乐器架设到舞台上
set up on stage,
don't you?
Claire, go and turn those stage lights on
and get these boys going up there.
克蕾儿，去把舞台的灯打开
Chicken wire?
鸡笼？
What do you say we set up for sound check?
我们来准备试音如何？
Excuse me, sonny,
I guess I'll give this to you.
先生，因为你是最高的
所以我把它交给你
You're the tallest one.
Okay, what is it?
这是什么？
Well, that there is a list of the songs
you boys will be playing tonight.
上面写了你们今晚
要演唱的歌曲
Man, I don't think we know any
of the songs on this list.
上面没有一首歌是我们会的
This list doesn't mean anything.
They're just requests.
不用怕！只是一张点歌单
Do our regular set.
First tune!
表演固定的曲目，起音
Give Me Some Loving.
One, two.
“给我一点爱”
一、二
One, two, three, four.
一、二、三、四
干！
What are those damn freak
pecker heads playing?
那些死混蛋弹些什么啊？
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
晚安！先生女士们
很高兴今晚能在这里
We're glad to be here
in Kokomo tonight.
We're the Good Old Blues
Brothers Boys Band from Chicago.
我们是来自芝加哥的
老好布鲁斯兄弟乐团
We sure hope you'll like our show.
希望各位喜欢我们的表演
我是艾伍德，他是杰克
I'm Elwood.
This is my brother Jake.
Well, my temperature's rising
and my feet on the floor
我的体温逐渐上升
我的两脚勉强站着
Crazy people knockin'
'Cause they wanted some more
人们疯狂的牛饮
因为他们还想要
Let me in, baby
I don't know what you got
让我进去，宝贝
别让我空等待
You better take it easy
'Cause this place is hot
你热情的火焰
让我无力抵抗
And I'm so glad you made it
我们突破重重障碍
That ain't no Hank Williams song!
这不是汉克威廉斯的歌
Give me some loving
给我一点爱
Get off the stage!
滚下台来！
Give me some loving
Every day
Why'd they turn off the lights?
灯光为什么没了？
Maybe they blew a fuse.
保险丝可能烧坏了
I don't think so, man.
我觉得他们是故意
把灯关掉的
Those lights are off on purpose.
We gotta figure out something
these people like, and fast!
我们要快点想出一首
他们喜欢的歌
I got it.
Remember the theme from Rawhide?
想到了！
记得“皮鞭”的主题曲吗？
The old favorite.
Rowdy Yates.
老歌，是洛迪叶慈唱的
What key?
A.
什么调？
A调，乡村歌曲的调门
Good country key.
Rawhide in A.
A调的“皮鞭”
Rollin ', rollin ', rollin'
前进！前进
Though the streams are swollen
越过暴涨的溪水
Keep them dogies rollin'
驱赶牛群向前进
Rawhide
皮鞭
The rain and wind and weather
Hellbent for leather
无视恶劣的天气
归心似箭的赶路
Wishin' my gal was by my side
希望爱人陪伴身旁
All the things I'm missin'
为了生活忍受风霜
Good vittles,
love and kissin'
美食、爱情和香吻
Are waiting at the end of my ride
在旅途的终点等待
Move 'em on
Head 'em up
驱赶牛群
踏上旅途
Head 'em up
Move 'em on
长路漫漫
带领牛队
Move 'em on
Head 'em up
赶着牛群
勇敢向前
Rawhide
Cut 'em out
皮鞭一挥，牛只归队
Ride 'em in
赶牛入栅
Cut 'em out
放牛吃草
Ride 'em in, Rawhide
皮鞭一挥，安全返家
Move 'em on
Head 'em up
Rawhide
Cut 'em out
Ride 'em in
Ride 'em in,
Rawhide
Yah!
Theme from the TV show Rawhide.
Thank you.
连续剧“皮鞭”的主题曲
谢谢各位
We'd like to do a favorite
of the horn section.
下面带来一首抒情歌曲
希望大家喜欢
We hope it's one of yours.
Sometimes it's hard to be a woman
难为女人
Giving all your love
将所有的爱
To just one man
给唯一的男人
And if you love him
你如果爱他
Oh, be proud of him
就以他为荣
'Cause after all
因为到底
He's just a man
他只是男人
Stand by your man
支持你的男人
Give him two arms to cling to
让你温暖的怀抱
And something warm to come to
成为他坚强的依靠
When nights are cold and lonely
在寂寞孤单的夜晚
Stand by your man
支持你的男人
And tell the world you love him
告诉全世界你爱他
Keep giving all the love you can
给他你所有的爱
Stand by your man
支持你的男人
And show the world you love him
告诉全世界你爱他
Keep giving all the love you can
给他你所有的爱
Baby
宝贝
Stand by your man
支持
你的男人
“男厕”
Well, folks, it's time to call it a night.
各位，到了说再见的时候
But do what you feel, and
keep both feet on the wheel.
开车小心，千万别用脚开
You don't have to go home
but you can't stay here.
你可以不用回家
不过餐厅要打烊了
So, till next time:
我们下次再见
Move 'em on Head 'em up
驱赶牛群
踏上旅途
Head 'em up
Move 'em on
长路漫漫
带领牛队
Move 'em on
Head 'em up
Rawhide
皮鞭一挥
Cut 'em out
Ride 'em in
皮鞭一挥
牛只归队
Ride 'em in
Cut 'em out
赶牛入栅
放牛吃草
Cut 'em out
Ride 'em in, Rawhide
皮鞭一挥，安全返家
Rawhide
皮鞭
Let's get the hell
out of here.
我们闪人吧！
Shit, I wanna tell you boys that's some
of the best goddamn music we've had
妈的！我告诉你
我很久没有请到
这么棒的乐团了
at the Country Bunker in a longtime.
Sorry we couldn't remember
The Wreck of the Old 97.
抱歉！我们不会唱
“97的沉船”
Why, hell!
没关系！下次来会唱就行了
You guys can learn it next
time when you come back.
Bob, about our money for tonight.
巴布
今天晚上表演的酬劳…
That's right.
对了！
$200
两百块
and you boys drank $300 worth of beer.
另外你们喝了三百块的啤酒
When we first came in the bar lady
never charged us for the first round
我们刚到的时候
吧台的小姐招待我们喝酒
so, like, we figured beer was
complimentary for the band.
我们还以为是免费赠送的
Beer was, like, complimentary
for the band, you know.
No.
不是
Well, I'll just go out and take up
a collection from the boys.
那我出去跟他们收钱
Well, I'll tell you,
I sure would appreciate it.
谢谢你的帮忙
I say this trip is nowhere, man.
我们是在浪费时间
I say we gotta quit.
干脆放弃算了
What? Quit?
什么？放弃？
Well, I wish you guys
would make up your mind.
你们最好快点决定
Otherwise, I've gotta call Mr. Ronzini
不然我就要打电话
联络假期酒店了
at the Holiday Inn and
get our old gig back.
Back at the Armada Room?
回酒店表演？
Listen, they want us to pay
for the beer we drank.
他们要我们付啤酒钱
So you guys better split.
你们最好快闪
The next gig is
gonna be dynamite!
下一场表演一定会造成轰动
Huge! You'll see.
你们相信我
I say we give The Blues Brothers
just one more chance.
我们再给他们最后一次机会
Why not?
If the shit fits, wear it!
反正都已经上了贼船了
Scoot over, goddamn it!
该死！坐进去点
Boys look a little upset.
他们看起来很失望
Hey, man. Don't worry.
We got a couple of days.
别担心！老兄
我们还有几天的时间
We'll get the Penguin's tax money.
一定会有钱给院长缴税的
I mean, look.
再说
我们明天就会见到史莱
We got an appointment
to see Mr. Sline tomorrow.
Everything's gonna be all right.
不会有事的
Let's skate.
我们走吧！
Goddamn it.
该死
“来自纳许维尔”
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Are you The Good Ole Boys?
请问你们是老好男孩吗？
Yeah, that's right.
没错！我是主唱兼驾驶
塔克麦考瑞
I'm Tucker McElroy,
lead singer,
driver of the Winnebago.
I'd like to talk to you,
but we're running very late.
我现在没时间跟你聊天
My name is Jacob Stein,
American Federation
我是雅各史坦
美国音乐家联合工会代表
of Musicians Union,
Local 200.
I've been sent here to see if you
gentlemen are carrying your permits.
我是来检查你们的许可证
Our what?
我们的什么？
Your union cards.
你们的工会卡，请拿出来
May I see your cards, please?
Suppose we ain't got no union cards
and we go in and start playing anyway.
要是我们没有工会卡
就进去表演呢？
What you gonna do about that?
你们打算怎么办？
不让我们表演？
You gonna stop us? Stein?
史坦
You gonna look pretty funny trying to eat
corn on the cob with no fucking teeth!
当心我打的你满地找牙
Listen,
我去找老板巴布谈谈
let me talk to Bob,
the owner.
See if we can put your band
on contract waivers for tonight.
看他愿不愿意
让你们非法打工
I don't want you to move from this spot.
- Just let me handle this.
你们待在原地不要动
交给我来处理
We'll, uh...
We'll talk to Bob.
我们会跟巴布谈
Get in the car and start her up.
你先去发车
You know you boys owe me a lot of money
for that beer you drank tonight!
你们还欠我一堆啤酒钱
Goddamn it!
他妈的！
Bob, we loved playing here tonight.
我们很高兴能来这里表演
My brother's writing out
an American Express traveler's cheque
我叫我弟弟去开旅行支票了
to cover the extensive bar tab.
Well, I sure would appreciate it.
真是谢谢你
I'd better check up,
see how he's doing.
我过去看一下
支票需要我签名
See, I have to sign it, too.
I usually sit in the car and write it out
on the, uh, glove compartment lid.
通常我都是利用
置物箱的箱盖来写字
Okay?
I need a pencil.
需要一枝铅笔
Were them guys from the union?
不是工会派他们来的吗？
Union?
What the hell union?
什么鬼工会？
Those boys skipped out of here
owing me a lot of money for beer.
那些家伙没付啤酒钱就溜了
What the hell are you guys
all dressed up for?
你们干嘛打扮成这样？
We're The Good Ole Boys!
我们是老好男孩
You're The Good Ole Boys?
你们是老好男孩？
A.F.M. Shit!
美国音乐家联合会个屁
Our Lady of Blessed Acceleration,
don't fail me now!
亲爱的加速器
千万不要让我们失望
I don't believe it!
有没有搞错！
又是那辆烂道奇车
It's that shitbox Dodge again.
The bastards are ours now!
他们这次跑不掉了
Holy shit!
我的妈呀！
Boys, you're in big trouble.
男士们！你们倒大楣了
Maury, you owe me.
莫瑞，你欠我人情
We'll play anywhere,
anytime, for anybody.
任何地点、时间
我们都能表演
Put us in, uh,
the Double Up Lounge,
像是摩根公园戏院
或者是水晶酒店
or the Morgan Park Theater,
or the Crystal.
We always knocked them
dead in those joints.
那些地方的观众爱死我们了
Discos.
They're all discos.
迪斯可
到处都是迪斯可音乐
Singles.
Mixed singles, gay singles.
单曲、混合单曲…
Those people like to tumble and carry on.
They like to dance with each other.
现在的人喜欢找人跳舞
We are a dance band.
舞曲是我们的专长
I don't know, boys.
I just don't know.
老兄，我真的很怀疑
Times have changed,
you know what I mean?
你明白吗？时代变了
What are you guys gonna do?
The same act?
你们还打算唱老歌？
You wear the same farchadat suits.
继续穿同一套西装？
You'll scare people away.
你们会把观众吓跑
Don't you ever wear blue jeans or jumpsuits
like Wayne Cochran and the C.C. Riders?
试过像其他歌手那样
穿牛仔裤或工作服吗？
You gotta come through for us.
你一定要帮我们想办法
We need $5,000, fast.
我们需要尽快筹到五千块
$5,000?
五千块？
Who do you think you are?
The Beatles?
你们以为自己是披头四啊？
You know the size hall you gotta
work to take in that kind of money?
知道要唱多大型的场地
才能赚到五千块？
We'll fill any hall in the country.
我们任何场地都愿意唱
You guys familiar with
the Palace Hotel ballroom?
听过宫殿旅馆的舞厅吗？
Never heard of it.
没听过
Nice place up north.
在北边，风景优美
Built in the '40s on Lake Wazapamani.
40年代盖的湖滨旅馆
That seats 5,000.
可以容纳五千人
You guys fill that place,
you can make $5,000, easy.
只要客满
你们就能赚进五千块
Book us for tomorrow night.
帮我们订明天晚上
Hold it!
Tomorrow night?
等一下！明天晚上？
A gig like that, you gotta
prepare the proper exploitation.
这种大型的表演
必须有适当的宣传
I know about that stuff.
I been exploited all my life.
我晓得
我一辈子都在自我推销
Forget it. There's no way with you guys.
Forget about it.
算了吧！你们不可能成功的
Say, how's Mrs. Sline?
对了！你太太好吗？
I might have some information
she'd like to know.
我有她想知道的八卦消息
You blackmailing me?
你恐吓我？
If you wanna put it that way.
Maury, we need this gig!
随你怎么说
莫瑞，我们需要这场表演
We're on a mission from God.
我们是上帝派来的
You get us the hall, and I guarantee
we'll pack them in from miles around.
帮我们订场地
我们保证一定会座无虚席
What do you say?
Okay. I'll get you the Palace Hotel.
好吧！我打电话去订
I'll print up showbills.
I'll make
顺便，我会把海报印好
the place look real pretty, okay?
I don't think you guys
are gonna gross dollar one.
我不认为你们的表演能赚钱
But if you do, I want a
taste of the gate, okay?
要是能赚钱，我就要分红
同不同意？
Thanks, Maury.
Let's go, boys!
谢了！莫瑞
走吧！兄弟们
Listen,
孩子们，你们听我说过
杰克和艾伍德的事
you boys heard me talk about Jake and Elwood.
Well, they used to live here,
just like you.
他们以前也住这里
And I used to sing to them,
just like with you.
我以前也唱歌给他们听
Tonight,
杰克和艾伍德
今天晚上有场表演
Jake and Elwood are
going out to sing and play
to raise money to help you children.
是为了帮你们筹钱
Your lazy butts are in this, too!
你们应该要帮忙
So get up on that wagon.
全部给我上车去
We're going up north
to put the word in the streets.
我们要出发去帮他们宣传
Tonight only,
the fabulous Blues Brothers,
布鲁斯兄弟
今晚唯一一场表演
Rhythm and Blues Revue
节奏蓝调歌舞
at the Palace Hotel ballroom,
Route 16,
宫殿旅馆的舞厅
位于16号公路旁
Lake Wazapamani.
瓦沙帕马尼湖
The fabulous Blues Brothers,
布鲁斯兄弟表演乐团
Show Band and Revue.
There you go, boy.
拿去吧！
All right, man!
干的好！
Check it out!
快来看哦！
Tonight only!
今晚唯一一场
来自芝加哥
From Chicago!
The Blues Brothers.
布鲁斯兄弟
节奏蓝调歌舞
Rhythm and Blues Revue.
One night only!
The fabulous...
唯一一场！了不起的…
Blues Brothers Show Band and Revue.
布鲁斯兄弟表演乐团
You!
On the motorcycle!
喂！骑摩托车的
You two girls!
喂！对面的女孩
Tell your friends!
好东西和好朋友分享
免费停车
Free parking.
$2 cover charge only, folks!
门票只要两块钱
That's a lot of entertainment.
只要两块钱，保证物超所值
For $2.
Will you please put this
in the window, lady,
可不可以把它帖到窗户上
很重要的
because it's real important.
Tonight only, from Chicago,
今晚唯一一场
来自芝加哥的…
the fabulous Blues Brothers,
布鲁斯兄弟
Rhythm and Blues Revue,
节奏蓝调歌舞
for your dancing pleasure.
保证您随歌起舞
And it's ladies' night tonight
今天晚上是“女士之夜”
at the Palace Hotel ballroom.
地点在宫殿旅馆的舞厅
"Tonight only, the Blues Brothers,
今晚唯一一场
布鲁斯兄弟蓝调节奏歌舞
"genuine Rhythm and Blues Show and Revue.
"Palace Hotel ballroom.
Tonight only. "
宫殿旅馆的舞厅，唯一一场
How we doing?
如何？
嗯…
So far we covered Lake, McHenry
我们已经跑了湖郡
麦亨利郡
and part of DuPage County.
还有杜佩奇郡的一部分
Good.
Let's get to the gig.
很好！我们该准备表演了
What is it?
怎么搞的？
We're out of gas.
我们没油了
Oh, shit.
糟了！
Wow, a classic.
What a room!
哇！正点
好棒的场地
This place is gonna swing tonight.
今天晚上一定会很轰动的
It's a fucking barn.
We'll never fill it.
这么大！不可能坐满的
We've gotta fill this hall tonight.
A lot of young children are depending on it.
非坐满不可
这关系到许多小孩子的幸福
Young children?
Why, what do you mean?
小孩子？你是什么意思？
Jake and Elwood are donating the
band's share of the door money
杰克和艾伍德
要捐出乐团的门票收入
to pay the taxes on the Saint
Helen's Orphanage in Calumet City.
帮圣海伦孤儿院
还清欠国税局的钱
What?
什么？
We're out of gas.
Yep.
我们没油了
Mind if we fill her up?
对啊！我可以加油吗？
Nope.
I said we're out of gas.
不可以，因为我们没油了
Tanker truck's late.
Should have been here two hours ago.
油罐车两个钟头前就该到的
Uh, it's always late on Thursdays.
每次一到星期四就迟到
I guess we'll have to wait.
看样子，我们只好继续等了
Yeah.
是啊！
“宫殿旅馆”
Excuse me, sir.
先生？
Yes, you. Could you fill it up with premium,
please, and check under the hood?
对，麻烦加满92无铅
顺便检查一下车子
Sure.
没问题
You, uh, want I should, uh,
要洗掉挡风玻璃上
的虫虫吗？
wash the dead bugs off the windshield?
Oh, no. Don't worry.
I'm in kind of a hurry.
不用了，我赶时间
Where in the hell are they?
他们死到哪去了？
So, uh, maybe you'd like to come by
and see the show.
或许你可以过来看我们表演
Oh, um, I'm awfully sorry,
真的很抱歉
可是我已经约了人吃晚饭了
but I do have a prior dinner engagement.
“唯一一场：布鲁斯兄弟”
Thanks, Marvin.
马文，谢谢
Debbie, get me Troopers Daniel and Mount.
帮我接州警局的丹尼和蒙特
I don't see those Blues Brothers.
我没看到布鲁斯兄弟
We'll wait.
我们继续等
Okay, you're all set.
好啦！全部搞定
That'll be, uh, $94.
一共是94块
Here's $95.
Thank you, Elwood.
谢谢你！这里是95块
Okay.
And that's $1 change.
哦！这是找你的一块钱
Oh, keep the change.
不用找了
Oh, thanks.
谢谢
Uh, so, look.
Uh, if your date
万一，要是你晚餐…
don't work out tonight for any reason,
吃的不是很愉快的话
there's a motel up on the interstate.
在州界处有一间旅馆
Uh, maybe we could,
say, uh, meet
也许我们可以…见个面
around, uh, midnight?
12点左右如何？
I'll think about it,
Elwood, okay?
艾伍德，让我想一想
好
Bye.
再见
Son of a bitch!
他妈的！
Come on!
快走啊！
We're really late.
You better step on it, man.
我们来不及了，开快一点
Yeah.
好
I always like to perform for angry mobs.
我喜欢为愤怒的观众表演
You can't quit now.
你不能现在落跑
What can they be doing?
他们搞什么啊？
My head hurts.
我头好痛
That Night Train's a mean wine.
那瓶一定是假酒
You'd better get bright!
We got a show to do.
保持清醒，我们得表演
Then we gotta figure out some
way to collect that gate money,
而且还得想办法收门票钱
get it to the Cook County
Assessor's office
再一大早把钱交进国税局
as soon as they open in the morning.
We want the show!
快表演！快表演
Gentlemen,
I'm leaving.
各位，我可要闪了
Man, we were so close.
差一点就成功了
Hey, you guys know Minnie The Moocher?
你们知道“乞丐咪妮”吗？
I knew a hooker once named Minnie Mazola.
我认识一个同名的妓女
No! The song Minnie the Moocher.
不是，“乞丐咪妮”是一首歌
Yeah. So what?
知道又怎样？
音乐
Hit it!
Hey folks here's a story 'bout
这是乞丐咪妮的故事
Minnie the Moocher
She was a low-down hoochie coocher
一个出身低贱的舞女
She was the roughest toughest frail
一个倔强剽悍的女郎
But Minnie had a heart
咪妮很有野心
As big as a whale
野心大过鲸鱼
She messed around with a bloke named Smokey
她和史莫基混在一起
She loved him though he was cokey
虽然知道他不是好人
He took her down to Chinatown
史莫基带她去中国城
And he showed her how
to kick the gong around
他教咪妮要如何吸毒
She had a dream about the King of Sweden
咪妮梦想能变成凤凰
He gave her things that she was needin'
史莫基对她有求比应
He gave her a home built of gold and steel
他送给咪妮一栋黄金屋
A diamond car with the platinum wheels
一辆白金钢圈的钻石车
This is glue.
Strong stuff.
这是强力喷胶，威力惊人
What the hell
are you doing?
你到底搞什么鬼？
This can is from a surplus disposal run.
这瓶铁罐虽然不起眼
Fifteen overcharged ounces
里面装的却是非混合的
异丙基丁烷单硫酸盐
of pure uncompounded isoproponyl
butane monosulphide.
When combined with oxygen
and a little heat
当它和氧气、热结合后
it will cause a rapid expansion.
会引起快速的膨胀
Poor Min, poor Min
可怜的咪妮，可怜的咪妮
Poor Min
可怜的咪妮
Okay, let's take them!
Wait a minute.
把他们捉起来
I've never even heard these
boys sing, all right?
等一下！
我从来没听过他们唱歌
All right.
好吧！
They're not going no place.
反正他们是逃不掉的
All right, cover all exits!
Let's go! Come on! Hurry up!
我们走！守住所有的出口
动作快
Move it!
动作快！
Who wants an Orange Whip?
你们谁要橘子蛋奶？
要不要？
Orange Whip?
Three Orange Whips.
三杯橘子蛋奶
Excuse us.
抱歉
Good evening, ladies.
女士们，晚安
One, two. One, two, three, four.
一、二
一、二、三、四
Now, ladies and gentlemen
各位先生女士
it is the distinct pleasure of
the management to present to you
主办单位很荣幸为您介绍
the evening's star attraction.
今晚的主角
Here they are, back after their
exclusive three-year tour
他们刚结束
欧洲、斯堪的纳维亚半岛
of Europe, Scandinavia and the Subcontinent.
和次大陆
历时三年的巡回演出
Won't you welcome, from
Calumet City, Illinois,
让我们欢迎来自伊利诺州
the show band of Joliet
Jake and Elwood Blues.
杰克和艾伍德的表演乐团…
The Blues Brothers!
布鲁斯兄弟！
One, two.
One, two, three, four.
一、二
一、二、三、四
We're so glad to see so many of
you lovely people here tonight.
很高兴能和大家见面
We'd especially like to welcome
all the representatives
我们要感谢
来自伊利诺州的执法代表
of Illinois' law enforcement community,
who have chosen to join us here
特地抽空来宫殿旅馆
观赏今晚的演出
in the Palace Hotel ballroom at this time.
We certainly hope you all enjoy the show.
希望你们喜欢今晚的表演
And remember that no matter who you are
记住！不管你是谁
不管你是以何为生
and what you do to live,
thrive and survive
there're still some things
that make us all the same.
我们还是有共通点
You. Me. Them.
Everybody.
你，我，他们，每个人
每个人
Everybody
Needs somebody
都需要某个人
Everybody
每个人
Needs somebody to love
都需要爱某个人
Someone to love
某个人来爱
Sweetheart to miss
甜心来想念
Sugar to kiss
蜜糖来亲吻
I need you
我需要你、你、你
I need you, you, you
In the morning
清晨时
You
When my soul's on fire
当我的灵魂孤单醒来
You
Sometimes I feel
我感到
I feel a little sad inside
我感到内心的悲伤
When my baby mistreats me
当我的宝贝错待我
我无法，无法
I never; never find a
place to hide I need you
找到地方躲藏
我需要你
Sometimes I feel
我感到
I feel a little sad inside
我感到内心的悲伤
When my baby mistreats me
当我的宝贝错待我
I never never find a
place to hide I need you
我无法，无法找到地方躲藏
我需要你
People, when you do find
that special somebody,
各位
当你找到那个特别的人
you gotta hold that man,
hold that woman,
要握住那个男人或女人
love him, please him,
squeeze her, please her!
爱他、满足他
抱她、取悦她
Signify your feelings
with every gentle caress
以亲吻来表示你的感情
because it's so important
to have that special somebody
因为你需要那个特别的人
to hold, to kiss,
to miss,
你可以握她、亲她、想她
to squeeze and please!
你可以拥抱她、取悦她
Everybody needs somebody
每个人都需要某个人
Everybody
每个人
Needs somebody to love
都需要爱某个人
Someone to love
某个人来爱
Sweetheart to miss
甜心来想念
Sugar to kiss
蜜糖来亲吻
I need you
我需要你、你
In the morning
清晨时
When my soul's on fire
当我的灵魂孤单醒来
When there ain't no
one around I need you
当我独自孤单一人
我需要你
I need you, you, you
当我独自孤单一人
我需要你
I need you
Thank you.
That was for Wilson Pickett.
谢谢！那首歌是给威尔森的
This is dedicated to the
late, great Magic Sam.
下面这首歌
要献给“神奇”山姆
One, two.
One, two, three, four.
一、二
一、二、三、四
Come on baby don't you wanna go
来吧！宝贝
难道你不想走
Come on baby don't you wanna go
来吧！宝贝
难道你不想走
Back to that same old place
回到过去的老地方
Sweet home Chicago
甜蜜的家乡芝加哥
Six and three is nine
六加三是九
Nine and nine is 18
九九是十八
Look there brother baby
and you'll see what I seen
看过去！宝贝
你是否看见
Baby, don't you wanna go
Back to that same old place
Sweet home Chicago
Come on
Baby, don't you wanna go
Back to that same old place
Sweet home Chicago
The Mafia's after us now.
黑手党追来了
You guys were hot!
你们实在太棒了！
我要帮你们出唱片
You were great! Insane.
I've got to record you.
Bullshit.
放屁
Bullshit?
I don't bullshit.
我不放屁的
I'm president of Clarion Records
我是喇叭唱片的老板
东岸最大的唱片公司
the largest recording company
on the Eastern seaboard.
So what?
又怎样？
Here's $10,000.
这里是一万块
An advance on your first recording session.
你们灌唱片的头款
Is it a deal?
愿不愿意啊？
Yeah. Sure, it's a deal.
当然…当然愿意了
Yeah. Sure, it's a deal!
当然…当然是愿意啦！
Listen, all these cops out here,
they're sort of waiting for us.
所有的警察都守在外面
We gotta get out with nobody seeing us.
You know a back door out?
我们必须偷偷溜出去
知道其他的出路吗？
Sure. I used to be head bouncer
here back in the '70s.
知道！
想当年我可是这里的保镖
There's an electrical service duct
right behind your drummer's riser.
鼓手背后
就是维修电路用的通道
Do us a favor.
帮我一个忙
Take $1,400
拿一千四百块
and give it to Ray's Music
Exchange in Calumet City
给“雷乐器交换店”
剩下的就交给乐团
and give the rest to the band.
You got it.
Thanks.
没问题
谢了
再见
Me and Elwood are gonna make a break for it.
我和艾伍德先闪了
你们继续表演
You and the band keep playing.
Something's wrong.
事情不太对
Where's Jake?
杰克人呢？
Where'd those Blues Brothers go?
他们去哪了？
I sure hope this thing leads someplace.
我希望这条路出的去
Elwood,
we're gone, man.
老弟，我们已经成功了
Who is that girl?
这女的是谁啊？
Well, Jake.
杰克
You look just fine down there
你的气色不错嘛！
slithering in the mud like vermin.
很像土里的寄生虫
No problem.
别担心
You're not gonna get away from me this time.
你这次是死定了
Check that out!
Let's go!
有枪声！快走
It's good to see you,
sweetheart!
宝贝，真高兴看到你
You contemptable pig.
你这只猪！
I remained celibate for you.
我没有嫁人都是因为你
I stood at the back of a cathedral
我站在教堂的后面
waiting,
in celibacy, for you
傻傻的等着你
with 300 friends and relatives in attendance.
还有来观礼的
三百位亲戚朋友
My uncle hired the best
Romanian caterers in the state.
我叔叔请来了
最棒的罗马尼亚外烩
To obtain the seven limousines
for the wedding party
为了租那七辆加长礼车
my father used up his last favors
with Mad Pete Trullo.
我爸爸用光了所有的交情
So for me, for my mother,
所以为了我、我妈
my grandmother,
my father, my uncle,
我祖母、我爸
我叔叔…
and for the common good
I must now kill you and your brother.
我要杀了你们两兄弟
为民除害
Oh, please don't kill us!
求求你！不要杀我们
Please, please, don't kill us.
拜托！不要杀我们
You know I love you, baby!
你知道我爱的是你
我不是故意失约的
I wouldn't leave you!
It wasn't my fault!
You miserable slug!
你这个贱人！
You think you can talk
your way out of this?
你以为我还会上当吗？
你骗了我
You betrayed me!
No, I didn't. Honest!
我真的没有骗你
I ran out of gas!
我的汽油用光了
I had a flat tire!
我的轮胎爆了
我没钱坐计程车
I didn't have enough money for cab fare!
My tux didn't come
back from the cleaners.
我的燕尾服被干洗店弄丢了
And old friend came in from out of town!
我的老朋友来拜访我
Someone stole my car!
我的车子被偷了
当时突然地震、淹水
There was an earthquake!
A terrible flood!
Locusts! It wasn't my fault,
露露，我对天发誓
真的不是我的错
I swear to God!
Oh, Jake...
喔！杰克
Jake, honey.
杰克，亲爱的
Let's go.
我们走！
Take it easy.
别生气
You're going to totally
demolish the cars.
那辆车玩完了
You want to maybe consider going
after the Blues Brothers?
你觉得我们是不是该去
追布鲁斯兄弟？
It's 106 miles to Chicago.
距离芝加哥106英哩
We got a full tank of gas,
half a pack of cigarettes,
我们有一缸汽油和半包香烟
it's dark, and we're wearing sunglasses.
天黑了，我们要戴好墨镜
Hit it.
上路
Shit, man. Can't this damn
thing go any faster than this?
妈的！
这辆车不能跑快一点吗？
Bob, I think I've got a little problem.
巴布，有点不对劲
Goddamn, boy.
老兄，你怎么开的
糟了！
Don't you say a fucking word.
你最好给我闭嘴
“旅馆”
All units,
we have a signal 10-79.
各单位注意，1079号状况
“调查局”
Officers are in pursuit:
员警正全力追捕…
a black-and-white 1974 Dodge sedan
一部1974年
黑白相间的道奇轿车
southbound on 47.
47号公路上向南逃逸
Respond to signal 10-79.
附近巡逻车辆
请立即前往支援
Occupants of vehicle:
one Joliet Jake Blues,
乘客姓名分别是
杰克和艾伍德布鲁斯
one Elwood Blues.
Considered extremely dangerous.
Gruppenführer!
高危险人物
古泡芙！
Hey, Jake,
杰克！
I gotta pull over.
杰克，我得靠边停车
Southbound on State Highway 47.
在47号公路上往南逃逸
Hi! Wanna hand me the mike?
麻烦把通话器递给我
Thanks a lot.
谢了
This is car...
What number are we?
这是巡逻车…
号码是几号？
55.
55号
Car 55.
We're in a truck.
55号巡逻车
我们在货柜车里
Signal 10-79 still engaged.
1079号状况尚未解除
Vehicle traveling southbound
approaching Chicago city limits.
嫌犯持续向南逃逸
正接近芝加哥市
Commander advises will contact Chicago
precincts for a local intercept.
指挥官建议
联络芝加哥警方进行拦截
Maintain pursuit.
继续追捕
Use of unnecessary violence in the apprehension
of the Blues Brothers has been approved.
上级已经批准…
使用必要武力
逮捕布鲁斯兄弟
“地下快速车道”
“请开大灯”
Well, this is definitely Lower Wacker Drive.
果然有够快！
If my estimations are correct
如果我的估计正确
we should be very close to
我们应该非常接近
达利市长广场了
the Honorable Richard J. Daley Plaza.
That's where they got that Picasso.
广场上有毕加索的作品
没错
Yep.
Son of a bitch!
王八蛋！
There they are.
果然是他们
Oh, no!
What the fuck was that?
糟了！
怎么回事？
The motor.
it's thrown a rod.
马达要挂了
Is that serious?
不会吧？
很遗憾
Yep.
“前方道路施工”
Faster.
快一点
Holy shit!
我的妈呀！
I've always loved you.
我一直都爱着你
There it is!
就在前面
Come on!
走啊！
Sir, where's the office of
the Assessor of Cook County?
请问库克郡的
税务局办公室在哪？
Down the hall,
turn right.
大厅到底右转
Take the elevator to 1102.
搭电梯到1102
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你
Excuse me.
Did you see two guys come in here
请问一下
with black suits and hats,
one carrying a briefcase?
有没有看到两个
一身黑的家伙？
Yeah, I just sent them down there.
有啊！他们往那边去了
Thank you.
谢谢
Hold the door.
把门顶住
Let's go.
我们走！
“五分钟后回来”
Can I help you?
有事吗？
This is where they pay the taxes, right?
要缴税是不是来这边？
没错
Right.
This money is for the year's assessment on
the Saint Helen of the Blessed Shroud Orphanage
我们是来交…
in Calumet City, Illinois.
圣海伦孤儿院
欠伊利诺州的土地税
$5,000.
It's all there, pal.
全部一共是五千块
Stand back!
退后
Fire!
开枪！
And here is your receipt.
这是你们的收据
“悔改永远不嫌太迟”
Warden threw a party in the county jail
典狱长决定办舞会
Prison band was there and they began to wail
狱中乐团大显身手
The band was jumping and the joint began to swing
跳上舞台开始摇摆
You should have heard those
knocked-out jailbirds sing
听囚犯们快乐歌唱
Let's rock
一起摇滚
Everybody let's rock
大家一起摇滚
Everybody on the whole cell block
牢房里的每一个人
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock
跳到监狱都摇起来
Spider Murphy played the tenor saxophone
墨飞玩他的萨克斯风
Little Joe was blowing on the slide trombone
小乔吹他的伸缩喇叭
The drummer boy from Illinois
went crash, boom, bang
伊利诺州的鼓手敲敲打打
The whole rhythm section was the Purple Gang
整个乐团哼哼唱唱
Let's rock Everybody let's rock
一起摇滚
大家一起摇滚
Everybody on the whole cell block
牢房里的每一个人
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock
跳到监狱都摇起来
Dancing to the jailhouse rock
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
They were dancing
Dancing to the jailhouse rock
They were dancing,
dancing, dancing, dancing
Dancing to the jailhouse rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
They were dancing to the jailhouse rock
Dancing to the jailhouse rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
They were dancing to the jailhouse rock
Sad Sack was sitting on a block of stone
大牛悲伤的坐在石头上
Way over in the corner weeping all alone
一个人在角落偷偷哭泣
The warden said buddy
don't you be no square
典狱长安慰他
你何必死脑筋
if you can't get a partner
use a wooden chair
没有舞伴没关系
找张椅子也可以
Let's rock
一起摇滚
Everybody let's rock
大家一起摇滚
Everybody on the whole cell block
牢房里的每一个人
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock yeah
跳到监狱都摇起来
Dancing to the jailhouse rock
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
They was dancing
Dancing to the jailhouse rock
They were dancing,
dancing, dancing, dancing
Dancing to the jailhouse rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock
“工作人员”
Everybody on the whole cell block
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock
One, two.
One, two, three, four.
People, when you do
find that special somebody,
you gotta hold that man,
hold that woman,
love him, please him,
squeeze her, please her!
Signify your feelings
with every gentle caress,
because it's so important
to have that special somebody
to hold, to kiss,
to miss,
to squeeze and please!
到好莱坞，请来环球影城
请洽芭比